today let's tackle an interesting
algebra problem that challenges our
problemsolving
skills also this is considered as one of
the difficult math Olympiad questions so
stay tuned our goal is to find the value
of x that satisfies this equation
equation is x^2 - x Cub = 36 can you
solve it okay as the very first step If
You observe it closely you can see that
36 can be written as 27 + 9 and what is
27 it is 3 Cub right and also 9 is 3 S
right so this 36 can be returned as 3 2
+ 3 Cub but we need a minus sign here
and not plus so if you think a little
bit we can rewrite this 9 as Min - 3
Square as well and this 27 can be
written as minus of minus 3 Cub because
- 3 Cub is - 27 and adding one more
minus will make it a plus excellent so
it is clear that one of the answers to
this question will be minus three just
by hit and trial now in order to find
the other two Roots we will factorize
this equation for that first take this
36 on the left hand side and rearrange
this equation to make it minus of X Cub
+ x² - 36 = 0 or multiply both sides by
-1 to get XB - x² + 36 = 0 now in order
to factorize it using x + 3 rewrite this
as X Cub + 3 x² - 4 x² + 36 = 0 3 - 4
will be - x² only now take x² common
from this to get x2 * X + 3 and from
here take -4 as common to get -4 * x^2 -
9 this x^2 - 9 can be written as x - 3 *
x + 3 so far so good now take x + 3
common from both of them to get x + 3 *
x^2 - 4 * x - 3 = 0 or x + 3 * x^2 - 4 x
x + 12 = 0 now this will give x = -3 and
for this part we will be using the
quadratic equation formula we have a
which is equal to the coefficient of x²
= 1 then B which is the coefficient of x
= -4 and C which is the constant term as
12 plug them into the formula to get x =
minus of -4 +- under < t - 4 2 - 4 * 1 *
12 upon 2 which will give -4 +- under <
TK 16 - 48 or under < TK - 32 upon 2 now
this will introduce the imaginary term I
as under root minus 32 can be written as
under < tk-1 * under < TK 16 * 2 or 4 <
tk2 so X will become -4 + -4 < tk2 I
upon 2 or -2 + - 2 < tk2
I this is the solution to our problem
that was amazing isn't it so good
[Music]